LOISE MWANGI

P.O. Box 00100-30677, Nairobi, Kenya

(+254) 725 095013

Email: wanjirumwangi.learn@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/in/wanjiru-mwangi-a284b6184/

Portfolio: https://tc-mwangi.github.io/portfolio/

Github: https://github.com/tc-mwangi/

Personal Statement

A vibrant, driven and resourceful Full Stack Developer oriented towards building groundbreaking products with immersive user experiences. I enjoy working on challenging projects with diverse teams to challenge the norms and standard approaches to design.

Highlighted Software Applications

Squad - Full Stack Developer

March 2019

URL: https://github.com/tc-mwangi/squad

An eSports social gaming application for joining teams and participating in tournaments

- Implemented user authentication, profiles, follows, likes and real-time user feeds
- Fetched game information from IGDB video games API
- Created an API through Django RESTful API

Vybe - Scrum Master, Full Stack Developer

February 2019

URL: https://github.com/tc-mwangi/vybe-repo

A Geolocation trip-planner for discovering and rating rarely visited places in the country.

- Implemented user authentication, user profiles, post, share and follow functionality
- Built relational models using PostreSQL

Sojourner Blog - Full Stack Developer

January 2019

URL: https://sojourner-blog.herokuapp.com/

Personal blogging application

- Implemented user authentication, post, comment, delete and update functionality.
- Consumed random quotes API

Technical Skills

Strong: Python, Flask Framework, Django Framework, PostgreSQL, APIs, Heroku, Git, Javascript, jQuery, HTML5, CSS, Illustrator, Photoshop, InDesign, MacOS

Experienced: Angular, NodeJS, Electron, Three.js, MongoDB, Sketch, Figma, OpenCV, IOT, Windows, Linux, RaspbianOS

Personal Skills

- Ability to work under pressure with minimal supervision
- Easily establish rapport with clients so to deliver products that exceed expectations
- Effective at resolving conflicts peacefully

Employment History

Architect, Tectura International, Kenya May 2017 - March 2018 Achievements and Responsibilities

- Design Lead in several projects
 - Secured projects through design competitions
 - Research, design and timely delivery of projects

Architect, Tarakibu Architects, Kenya April 2015 - December 2016 Achievements and Responsibilities

- Lead in design and development of several KFC franchise branches
- Project Management, supervision and documentation of ongoing projects

Academic Qualification

Moringa School November 2018 - April 2019 Software Development (Full Stack)

Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology May 2008 - May 2014 Bachelor of Architecture Relevant Courses

- Architectural Design
- Building Technology
- Urban Studies

Alliance Girls High School 2003 - 2006 Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education (KCSE)

Interests

- Gaming: Avid gamer participating in Fortnite, PubG and Unreal Tournament campaigns
- Digital Art: Collaborating with artists to create unique creations through digital manipulation
- Travelling: Enjoying the sights and sounds of exotic places during planned trips with friends

References

John Kinuthia
Partner

Tectura International Tel: 0721 550142

Email: jkinuthia@tectura-int.co.ke

Kanyua Waweru Partner Freelance Architect Tel: 0721 474535

Email: kanyua.architect@gmail.com